<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ssh on Mark Ramige: Appsec and Bug Bounties</title>
    <link>https://markramige.com/tags/ssh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ssh on Mark Ramige: Appsec and Bug Bounties</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/markramige/markramigecom&#39;&gt;Mark Ramige&lt;/a&gt; :: &lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#39;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; Licensed :: Powered by &lt;a href=&#39;http://gohugo.io&#39;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markramige.com/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using SSH on Windows 10 and WSL 2</title>
      <link>https://markramige.com/posts/using-ssh-on-windows-10-and-wsl-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markramige.com/posts/using-ssh-on-windows-10-and-wsl-2/</guid>
      <description>Since WSL was introduced several years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the same process for access my machines remotely. I&amp;rsquo;d run apt-get install openssh-server in WSL and open TCP port 22 in Windows Firewall. WSL 2 adds the extra step of needing to forward a port to the WSL VM. I decided to try using OpenSSH directly since it is now available natively on Windows.
Contents  Install sshd, ssh, and ssh-agent Run sshd and ssh-agent at boot Start sshd and ssh-agent now Create ssh key and add to ssh-agent Add public keys to authorized_keys and set correct permissions Disable password login and restart sshd Make Git for Windows use ssh-agent Set up WSL distributions to use ssh-agent Future improvements Conclusion  *Open a PowerShell prompt with administrator privileges*</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Hackernote Write-Up</title>
      <link>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-hackernote-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-hackernote-write-up/</guid>
      <description>This TryHackMe challenge gives you an IP address to attack and takes you through each step of the process until you get root on the box. It covers recon, investigation, exploitation, user enumeration, password brute-forcing, and privilege escalation. It requires some basic linux skills to get started.
Contents  Task 1 - Reconnaissance Task 2 - Investigate Task 3 - Exploit Task 4 - Attack Passwords Task 5 - Escalate  Task 1 - Reconnaissance  Which ports are open?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
