<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>services on Mark Ramige: Cybersecurity and Linux, mostly</title>
    <link>https://markramige.com/tags/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in services on Mark Ramige: Cybersecurity and Linux, mostly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/markramige/markramige.com&#39;&gt;Mark Ramige&lt;/a&gt; :: &lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#39;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; Licensed :: Powered by &lt;a href=&#39;http://gohugo.io&#39;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markramige.com/tags/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Windows PrivEsc Write-Up</title>
      <link>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-windows-privesc-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-windows-privesc-write-up/</guid>
      <description>This TryHackMe room gives us a vulnerable Windows Server 2019 virtual machine and demonstrates many different types of Windows privilege escalation techniques. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many challenges included in the room, but just knowing how many different ways attackers can gain elevated privileges on a Windows machine is valuable. In addition, several tools are provided that show us how easy it is to automate checking for privesc vulnerabilities on Windows.
Contents  Service Exploits Registry Passwords Scheduled Tasks Insecure GUI Apps Startup Apps Token Impersonation Privilege Escalation Scripts  Service Exploits Task 3 First off, we&amp;rsquo;re checking permission on the daclsvc service.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://tryhackme.com/room/windows10privesc&#34;&gt;TryHackMe room&lt;/a&gt; gives us a vulnerable Windows Server 2019 virtual machine and demonstrates many different types of Windows privilege escalation techniques. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many challenges included in the room, but just knowing how many different ways attackers can gain elevated privileges on a Windows machine is valuable. In addition, several tools are provided that show us how easy it is to automate checking for privesc vulnerabilities on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#service-exploits&#34;&gt;Service Exploits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#registry&#34;&gt;Registry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#scheduled-tasks&#34;&gt;Scheduled Tasks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#insecure-gui-apps&#34;&gt;Insecure GUI Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#startup-apps&#34;&gt;Startup Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#token-impersonation&#34;&gt;Token Impersonation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#privilege-escalation-scripts&#34;&gt;Privilege Escalation Scripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-exploits&#34;&gt;Service Exploits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-3&#34;&gt;Task 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, we&amp;rsquo;re checking permission on the &lt;code&gt;daclsvc&lt;/code&gt; service. We notice that we have &lt;code&gt;SERVICE_CHANGE_CONFIG&lt;/code&gt; permissions and that the service runs with SYSTEM privileges. All we have to do is change the &lt;code&gt;BINARY_PATH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; of the service to make it run our reverse shell when the service starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-4&#34;&gt;Task 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Task 3, we check the permissions of the directory containing the &lt;code&gt;unquotedsvc&lt;/code&gt; service and notice that we can write to the directory. Since the &lt;code&gt;BINARY_PATH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; is unquoted, we copy our reverse shell to the directory and rename it to &lt;code&gt;common.exe&lt;/code&gt;. Since Windows will find &lt;code&gt;common.exe&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;Common Files&lt;/code&gt; it executes it instead of the intended service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-5&#34;&gt;Task 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that the registry entry for the &lt;code&gt;regsvc&lt;/code&gt; service has weak permissions. We can change the location of the service executable in the registry so that it runs our reverse shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-6&#34;&gt;Task 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;filepermsvc&lt;/code&gt; executable located at &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\File Permissions Service\filepermservice.exe&lt;/code&gt; is writeable by all users. All we have to do is replace it with our reverse shell executable and start the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;registry&#34;&gt;Registry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-7&#34;&gt;Task 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this task we&amp;rsquo;re checking the registry for programs that are set to run automatically at boot. These will be run with admin privileges. We notice that one program is writeable by all users. We can replace this program with our reverse shell and restart the machine to gain admin access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-8&#34;&gt;Task 8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We query the registry and find that the &lt;code&gt;AlwaysInstallElevated&lt;/code&gt; key is enabled. We can generate an installer that will automatically run with elevated privileges when it is installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-9&#34;&gt;Task 9&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can query the registry for the string &lt;code&gt;password&lt;/code&gt; to find user credentials. We find admin AutoLogin credentials and use the &lt;code&gt;winexe&lt;/code&gt; command in Kali to log on to the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-10&#34;&gt;Task 10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local admin user has saved their login credentials on the machine. We use the &lt;code&gt;cmdkey /list&lt;/code&gt; command to check for credentials and then the &lt;code&gt;runas /savecred&lt;/code&gt; command to take advantage of the saved credentials to run our reverse shell with admin privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-11&#34;&gt;Task 11&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have access to backup copies of the &lt;code&gt;SAM&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; files for our machine. We can use &lt;code&gt;creddump7&lt;/code&gt; to extract the NTLM hashes of the users on the system. We then use &lt;code&gt;hashcat&lt;/code&gt; to crack the admin password using a wordlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-12&#34;&gt;Task 12&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we have the NTLM hash, we can now use &lt;code&gt;pass the hash&lt;/code&gt; to login to the system without even needing to crack the hash to obtain the password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scheduled-tasks&#34;&gt;Scheduled Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-13&#34;&gt;Task 13&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine has a task set to run a PowerShell script every minute with SYSTEM privileges. In addition, we have permission to write to this file. All we have to do is add a line to the script to run our reverse shell executable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;insecure-gui-apps&#34;&gt;Insecure GUI Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-14&#34;&gt;Task 14&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pasting in a file location in the navigation input of the file open dialog bypasses the file type check that the application usually performs when opening a file. Since the application is running with admin privileges, it will also run our &lt;code&gt;cmd.exe&lt;/code&gt; with admin privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;startup-apps&#34;&gt;Startup Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-15&#34;&gt;Task 15&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have permissions to write to the admin startup directory. We&amp;rsquo;re going to create a new shortcut to our reverse shell executable in the startup directory so that it will run the next time the admin user logs on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;token-impersonation&#34;&gt;Token Impersonation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-16&#34;&gt;Task 16&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this task we&amp;rsquo;re exploiting a vulnerability in Windows to get local privilege execution. It turns out that if our user has &lt;code&gt;SeImpersonate&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;SeAssignPrimaryToken&lt;/code&gt; privileges, we can use those to gain &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-17&#34;&gt;Task 17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re again abusing &lt;code&gt;SeImpersonatePrivilege&lt;/code&gt; with the PrintSpoofer vulnerability to escalate local access to &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-escalation-scripts&#34;&gt;Privilege Escalation Scripts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-18&#34;&gt;Task 18&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All four of these tools check for most of the vulnerabilities that we&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with. Automated tools make it extremely easy for an attacker or penetration tester to find vulnerabilities on a Windows machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Windows PrivEsc Arena Write-Up</title>
      <link>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-windows-privesc-arena-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markramige.com/posts/tryhackme-windows-privesc-arena-write-up/</guid>
      <description>The Windows PrivEsc Arena TryHackMe room includes a vulnerable Windows 7 virtual machine and demonstrates several types of privilege escalation techniques. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many challenges included in the room, but just knowing how many different ways attackers can gain elevated privileges on a Windows machine is valuable. Also, many of the tasks show us how to use features of Metasploit to exploit Windows machines.
Contents  Registry Escalation Service Escalation Privilege Escalation Potato Escalation Password Mining Escalation  Registry Escalation Task 3 In this task we notice that C:\Program Files\Autorun Program\program.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The Windows PrivEsc Arena &lt;a href=&#34;https://tryhackme.com/room/windowsprivescarena&#34;&gt;TryHackMe room&lt;/a&gt; includes a vulnerable Windows 7 virtual machine and demonstrates several types of privilege escalation techniques. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many challenges included in the room, but just knowing how many different ways attackers can gain elevated privileges on a Windows machine is valuable. Also, many of the tasks show us how to use features of Metasploit to exploit Windows machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#registry-escalation&#34;&gt;Registry Escalation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#service-escalation&#34;&gt;Service Escalation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#privilege-escalation&#34;&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#potato-escalation&#34;&gt;Potato Escalation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#password-mining-escalation&#34;&gt;Password Mining Escalation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;registry-escalation&#34;&gt;Registry Escalation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-3&#34;&gt;Task 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this task we notice that &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\Autorun Program\program.exe&lt;/code&gt; is set to run at startup with administrator privileges. We also notice that the &lt;code&gt;Everyone&lt;/code&gt; user group has &lt;code&gt;FILE_ALL_ACCESS&lt;/code&gt; permission on &lt;code&gt;program.exe&lt;/code&gt;. This means we can replace the file with our own version and have that run at startup instead. Next we use &lt;code&gt;Metasploit&lt;/code&gt; to open a listener on our Kali box and generate a reverse shell to place on the Windows system as &lt;code&gt;program.exe&lt;/code&gt;. The next time we log on the reverse shell will run and we will be connected with administrator privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-4&#34;&gt;Task 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We check the registry for the &lt;code&gt;AlwaysInstallElevated&lt;/code&gt; key and notice that it is set to &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;. This means anything we install will have elevated privileges even if we install it as a normal user. We can generate a reverse shell installer with Metasploit and install it on our Windows machine. This will automatically connect to our listener and give us elevated permissions after installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-escalation&#34;&gt;Service Escalation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-5&#34;&gt;Task 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to control the registry entry for a Windows service means we can replace that executable file that is run when the service starts. In this task, we create a custom service executable that adds our normal user to the &lt;code&gt;administrators&lt;/code&gt; group. After we start the service, our user will have elevated privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-6&#34;&gt;Task 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task is similar to Task 5, but we don&amp;rsquo;t need registry permissions. We check the &lt;code&gt;filepermsvc&lt;/code&gt; executable and notice that the &lt;code&gt;Everyone&lt;/code&gt; group has &lt;code&gt;FILE_ALL_ACCESS&lt;/code&gt; permissions. This means we can just replace the executable with the same one we used in Task 5 and then start the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-8&#34;&gt;Task 8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;procmon&lt;/code&gt;, we notice that &lt;code&gt;dllsvc&lt;/code&gt; is calling &lt;code&gt;C:\Temp\hijackme.dll&lt;/code&gt;, but it is not found. We know that &lt;code&gt;C:\Temp&lt;/code&gt; is a writeable location, so we generate a reverse shell using Metasploit and copy it to that location. We can then start &lt;code&gt;dllsvc&lt;/code&gt; and our reverse shell will connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-9&#34;&gt;Task 9&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having permissions to configure a Windows service means we can change the command that runs when the service starts. We&amp;rsquo;re going to change the &lt;code&gt;daclsvc&lt;/code&gt; to run &lt;code&gt;net localgroup administrators user /add&lt;/code&gt;. This will add our user to the administrators group so that we have elevated privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-10&#34;&gt;Task 10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the details of the &lt;code&gt;unquotedsvc&lt;/code&gt;, we notice that the &lt;code&gt;BINARY_PATH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; is unquoted. Because there&amp;rsquo;s a space in the path and we can write to that directory, we can make Windows execute &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\Unquoted Path Service\common.exe&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\Unquoted Path Service\Common Files\unquotedpathservice.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-escalation&#34;&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-7&#34;&gt;Task 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We notice that as a normal user we can write to the &lt;code&gt;C:\ProgramData\Microsoft\Windows\Start Menu\Programs\Startup&lt;/code&gt; directory. Any programs that we add here will be run with administrator privileges. We create a reverse shell and place it in that directory and the log back in to connect to our listener with elevated privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-14&#34;&gt;Task 14&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this task we&amp;rsquo;re using Metasploit to suggest exploits to use based on our Windows machine version and update status. It suggests using &lt;code&gt;exploit/windows/local/ms16_014_wmi_recv_notif&lt;/code&gt;. We then run the exploit and gain elevated privileges in our reverse shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potato-escalation&#34;&gt;Potato Escalation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-11&#34;&gt;Task 11&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/foxglovesec/Potato&#34;&gt;Potato exploit&lt;/a&gt; allows us to run an arbitrary command with elevated privileges. For this task we&amp;rsquo;re going to use Potato to run &lt;code&gt;net localgroup administrators user /add&lt;/code&gt; which gives our normal user administrator privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;password-mining-escalation&#34;&gt;Password Mining Escalation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-12&#34;&gt;Task 12&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task has us look at a config file for possible secrets. We notice that the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Password&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; property value is base64 encoded. We can decode it to find the account password in clear text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-13&#34;&gt;Task 13&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to capture a memory dump of the running &lt;code&gt;iexplore.exe&lt;/code&gt; process. Running &lt;code&gt;strings&lt;/code&gt; on the dump file allows us to extract base64 encoded passwords that have been sent to a website.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
